karndean.com 2015-06-22

# Our Privacy Statement - Karndean UK & Ireland

Last Updated: 23 November 2011

**Karndean International Limited** (" **Karndean** ", " **we** ", " **us** " **or** " **our** ") **** understands how much you care about your personal information and the way it is collected and used. We are committed to protecting the integrity and confidentiality of all your information and appreciate the trust you place in us to take care of it and ensure that it is secure.

We have drawn up this privacy policy (" **Privacy Policy** "), which together with our Website Terms and Conditions inform you how we collect and use your information in a careful, sensible manner in compliance with the Data Protection Act 1998 (the " **Act** ") and how you may control our use of your personal information. By visiting karndean.com and our associated sites (" **Website(s)** "),unless otherwise specified, you are consenting to the procedures outlined in this Privacy Policy.

Karndean is a global organisation, with business processes, management structures, and technical systems that cross borders, both internal and external to the EU. This Privacy Policy applies to all our Websites except where a privacy policy or statement posted on a particular Karndean Website is specific to a particular Karndean service or location, in which case that privacy policy or statement will apply instead of this Privacy Policy. 

## Who controls the information collected? 

All personal information collected is in the control of **Karndean** **International Ltd** which is the "data controller" under the Act. Head Office address; Crab Apple Way, Vale Park, Evesham, Worcestershire. WR11 1GP (Company No. 01612506).

**What information may we collect from you?**

We collect, and process, the following types of information from you:

  * information that you provide to us when setting up or amending an account with us on our Websites or when subscribing to a service. For example, your name, address, email, contact telephone numbers, password and username;
  * information you provide to us when sending us comments or queries on the service we provide or information you voluntarily disclose to us by email or other means;
  * information that you provide if you report a problem with our Websites;
  * personal information provided directly by you when completing our online forms such as ‘Request a brochure’, ‘Find a retailer’ and ‘Request samples’;
  * information collected when you use our interactive services, including when you save information concerning your favourite floors, looks, colours and documents and any actions taken in relation to these interactive services; and 
  * information collected when you visit our Websites by way of cookies (see below for an explanation). This information is ‘anonymous’ and cannot be used to identify an individual.

If your personal information changes, or if you no longer require our services, we will endeavour to provide a way to correct, update or remove the personal data you have provided to us.

You should notify us of such changes immediately by our customer services team at [mydetails@karndean.co.uk](mailto:mydetails@karndean.co.uk)  ** __** (" **Email Address** ").

## What will we do with your information?

All the information we request and collect from you is essential to ensure that we continue to offer the best possible service to our customers. We will not request any information that does not directly relate to how we communicate with you directly or assist in improving our Websites and services to continually provide better customer service. 

We may use the information held about you in the following ways:

  * by transferring information between Karndean, our group companies, our service providers, independent retail and distribution network that will use the information solely for Karndean business; 
  * to ensure that our Websites are presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer; 
  * to provide you with updates, information, products or services (including marketing) that you request from us or which we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes (see Marketing and Consent below); 
  * to carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us; 
  * to allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so; 
  * to notify you about changes to our service or our Websites; 
  * by disclosing your personal information to selected third parties, who may provide you with information about goods and services which may be of interest to you, where you have consented to your information being used in this manner (see Marketing and Consent below); and 
  * by disclosing your personal information to third parties:

> if we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets;
> 
> if we or substantially all of our assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by us about our customers will be one of the transferred assets; and
> 
> without notice, if we are requested to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply the Website Terms and Conditions and/or any other agreements, or to protect the rights, property or safety of Karndean, our clients or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud prevention and credit risk reduction.

We may retain the data collected and store and access it for as long as is reasonably necessary for the purposes listed in this Privacy Policy. The data we collect from you may be transferred to and stored at a location outside the European Economic Area (EEA). By providing your personal data you agree to this transfer, storage or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

**Karndean does not** share, sell or rent personal information with third parties without your permission, other than for the limited exceptions listed above. 

## Are you under 18? 

We do not want to collect personal data from anyone under the age of 18. If you are under 18, you should not enter any data on our Websites.

## Cookies 

A small text file ‘Cookie’, is placed on to your computer’s hard drive through your web browser when you visit our Websites. This file enables us to enhance your current and future visits to the site, improve our service to you and obtain information from you about your internet usage. A cookie will enable our systems to recognise your browser and provide features specific to you. Cookies also enable us to identify whether or not all of the pages which you request are successfully received. All we can do with the cookie is write data to it. We can’t influence or control your computer. 

It is also a tool we can use to aggregate usage statistics about the site. This information enables us to recognise popular site features and further develop new ones, adding to the overall visitor experience of the site. For this we use a programme called Google Analytics, which is purely statistical data generating and cannot be used to find out the identity of a user. Whilst these cookies are anonymous, they do allow us to improve our Websites.

You are able to choose whether you wish cookies to be turned on or off.  The Help menu on the menu bar of most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie and how to disable cookies altogether.  If you choose to delete cookies or do not have your browser set to accept cookies from Karndean, you will still be able to view the site, however you will not experience a personalised visit nor will you be able to benefit from other personalised site offerings.

For more information regarding cookies, please follow this link: <http://www.aboutcookies.org/>

## Links

Our Websites may contain links to other sites for your convenience and information, including links to our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. We make every effort to ensure that all links are relevant, and that such links are only made to reputable websites. Karndean does not control such websites or their privacy practices, which may differ from our Privacy Policy. We do not endorse or make any representations about third-party websites. The personal data you choose to provide to or that is collected by these third parties is not covered by the Karndean Privacy Policy. We encourage you to review the privacy policy of any company before submitting your personal information on any third party site we link to.

## Marketing and Consent 

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes.  We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. 

You can exercise your right to prevent such processing, or to opt-out of receiving regular communications from us by  ticking the relevant box situated on the online form on which we collect your data or by contacting us on our Email Address. ** __** If you withdraw your consent to use of your personal information we will stop such use as soon as reasonably practicable.

## Security

We understand how important your personal information is and how essential it is to ensure that it remains safe and secured. 

We take every precaution to store all data in a controlled, secure environment to be accessed by authorised personnel only. Only Karndean employees who need the information to perform a specific job are granted access to your personal information. The servers on which we store your personal information are kept in a secure environment.

Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our Websites, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. You must not share this password with anyone. We accept no responsibility or liability for any loss you suffer or incur as a result of failing to comply with this condition.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of any data transmitted to our site; any such transmission is made at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

## PHISHING 

Phishing is the practice of deceiving someone into giving confidential information. Examples include falsely claiming to be a legitimate company when sending an email to a user, in an attempt to get the user to send private information that will be used for identity theft and fraud. ****

We will never ask you to send any personal details via email. If we require such details, for security reasons, we will ask you to contact us by telephone. Should you receive an email claiming to be from Karndean requesting this kind of information please do not respond but contact us immediately.

## How to access and update your information 

Karndean strives to ensure that your personal information is accurately recorded and stored. To protect your privacy, security and to avoid inaccuracies, we are happy to provide you with access to information we retain personal to yourself only. 

To request details of your personal data held by Karndean or if you would like to update or correct your information, please write to the following address;

Data Protection Team  
Karndean International Ltd  
Crab Apple Way  
Vale Park  
Evesham  
WR11 1GP  
United Kingdom

OR 

Email: [mydetails@karndean.co.uk](mailto:mydetails@karndean.co.uk)

Please quote your name and address and contact telephone number. We would be grateful if you could also provide brief details of the information required or changes to be made to our records as this will help us to accurately deliver your data requirements. Any access request may be subject to a fee of £10 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you. 

For the protection of all our customers, we will take all reasonable steps to confirm your identity before providing you with details of any personal information we may hold about you. 

## How to stop receiving information 

You may request not to receive marketing or other information which Karndean may send to you at any time by sending your request to;

Data Protection Team  
Karndean International Ltd  
Crab Apple Way  
Vale Park  
Evesham  
WR11 1GP  
United Kingdom

OR 

Email: [mydetails@karndean.co.uk](mailto:mydetails@karndean.co.uk)

## How to make a complaint 

If you have a complaint about how your personal data has been handled by Karndean, please write to us at;

Data Protection Team  
Karndean International Ltd  
Crab Apple Way  
Vale Park  
Evesham  
WR11 1GP  
United Kingdom

Your complaint must be in writing, sent by post and include your return address and contact information. We will then write to you within 15 days of receiving your complaint explaining what action has been taken and why. ****

## Privacy Policy Changes 

We may make changes to this Privacy Policy from time to time. Any changes we make to our Privacy Policy will be posted on our Websites and it is your responsibility to ensure that you refer to our Privacy Policy on occasion to ensure you are fully confident and happy with how we manage your personal information.

Your continued use of our Websites will indicate your acceptance of our revised Privacy Policy.
